<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Melissa Jay</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Melissa Jay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/media/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: center;}Goldwater Scholarship Graduate School Webinar
  Research Communication on Twitter
Enjoyed working with Drs. @jacob_oleson, Mary Charlton, and @rabalia on this research!
We propose a Bayesian approach for modeling age-adjusted rates from spatio-temporal datasets with excess zero counts. 1/ https://t.co/kH1LHRws2j
&amp;mdash; Melissa Jay (@MelissaJay) March 18, 2021  Excited to share our new paper in Statistics in Medicine (worked with Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melissa Jay</title>
      <link>/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/</guid>
      <description>img {border-radius: 50%;}Thanks for visiting my website! My name is Melissa Jay, and I am a fourth-year PhD Candidate in Biostatistics at the University of Iowa. I am working with Dr. Jacob Oleson on my dissertation research, which focuses on statistical methods for spatio-temporal modeling of cancer risk. We are developing methods for addressing zero inflation in the estimation of age-adjusted rates and methods for performing Bayesian mediation analyses with spatial datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Jay M, Oleson J, Charlton M, Arab A. A Bayesian approach for estimating age-adjusted rates for low-prevalence diseases over space and time. Statistics in Medicine. 2021;40(12):2922-2938.
Sewell DK, Penney J, Jay M, Zhang Y, Paulsen JS. Predicting an optimal composite outcome variable for Huntington&#39;s disease clinical trials. Journal of Applied Statistics. 2021;48(7):1339-1348. 
Jay M, Betensky RA. Displaying survival of patient groups defined by covariate paths: Extensions of the Kaplan-Meier estimator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Jay M, Oleson J, Charlton M, Arab A. A Bayesian approach for estimating age-adjusted rates for low-prevalence diseases over space and time. Statistics in Medicine. 2021;1-17.Enjoyed working with Drs. @jacob_oleson, Mary Charlton, and @rabalia on this research!
We propose a Bayesian approach for modeling age-adjusted rates from spatio-temporal datasets with excess zero counts. 1/ https://t.co/kH1LHRws2j
&amp;mdash; Melissa Jay (@MelissaJay) March 18, 2021  Jay M, Betensky RA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Presentations</title>
      <link>/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Modeling age-adjusted rates from spatio-temporal data sets with excess zero counts. Conference on Statistical Practice. Virtual presentation. 2021. 
Understanding &#34;how&#34; in a study of cause and effect: An introduction to mediation analysis in epidemiology. University of Iowa INFORMS Student Chapter Knowledge Cafe. Virtual presentation. 2020. 
Displaying survival of patient groups defined by covariate paths: Extensions of the Kaplan-Meier estimator. Eastern North American Region International Biometric Society Spring Meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service</title>
      <link>/service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/service/</guid>
      <description>Leadership
President, Biostatistics Student Organization (BSO), University of Iowa (2020 - 2021)
President &amp;amp; Student Founder, Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics Student Chapter, Colorado College (2013 - 2015)
Mentorship
Mentor, Goldwater Scholar Community Mentorship Program (2021 - Present)
Mentorship Program Committee Member, Goldwater Scholar Community Council (2020 - Present)
Mentor, Biostatistics Student Organization Mentorship Program (2020 - Present)
Competitive Scholarships Mentor, Dear Future Colleague (2020)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Iowa Summer Institute in Biostatistics
The Iowa Summer Institute in Biostatistics (ISIB) is an NIH-funded summer institute focused on introducing undergraduates to the field of biostatistics. While at Iowa, I have been actively involved with ISIB, serving as a Lab Instructor and participating in social activities to acquaint undergraduate scholars with our department and graduate school.
Lab Instructor for BIOS:4110 General Biostatistics (Summer 2019, Summer 2021)University of Iowa</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
