<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Melissa Jay</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Melissa Jay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for visiting my website! My name is Melissa Jay, and I am a fourth-year PhD Candidate in Biostatistics at the University of Iowa. I am working with Dr. Jacob Oleson on my dissertation research, which focuses on statistical methods for spatio-temporal modeling of cancer risk. We are developing methods for addressing zero inflation in the estimation of age-adjusted rates and methods for performing Bayesian mediation analyses with spatial datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Jay M, Oleson J, Charlton M, Arab A. A Bayesian approach for estimating age-adjusted rates for low-prevalence diseases over space and time. Statistics in Medicine. 2021;1-17. [paper]
Jay M, Betensky RA. Displaying survival of patient groups defined by covariate paths: Extensions of the Kaplan-Meier estimator. Statistics in Medicine. 2021;40:2024-2036. [paper]
Sewell DK, Penney J, Jay M, Zhang Y, Paulsen JS. Predicting an optimal composite outcome variable for Huntington&#39;s disease clinical trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Presentations</title>
      <link>/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Modeling age-adjusted rates from spatio-temporal data sets with excess zero counts. Conference on Statistical Practice. Virtual presentation. 2021. [slides]
Understanding &#34;how&#34; in a study of cause and effect: An introduction to mediation analysis in epidemiology. University of Iowa INFORMS Student Chapter Knowledge Cafe. Virtual presentation. 2020. [slides]
Displaying survival of patient groups defined by covariate paths: Extensions of the Kaplan-Meier estimator. Eastern North American Region International Biometric Society Spring Meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
